Nagacharan Teja Tangirala

SUMMARY

I am looking for an exciting development role with C++ or Rust. I am an Urban Mobility researcher with 8 years of Research and Development experience in studying electric mobility through high-performance simulations built in C++ and Rust.

EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

Technical University of Munich (TUM)

May 2021 - May 2024, Munich, Germany

- · Led a team of three researchers in a simulation-based study of cargo fleet electrification consisting of 150 trucks.
- Designed and implemented the electric truck fleet behavior in CityMoS (C++) traffic simulator.
- Supervised 12 student theses as part of their Bachelor's and Masters's courses.
- Published 5 research articles on Autonomous Fleets and Connected Vehicles simulations.
- · Doctoral research in Connected Vehicles Simulations by building a new simulator called Disolv (Rust).

Research Engineer

TUMCREATE

December 2019 - May 2021, Singapore

- · Developed synthetic trip generation module (Java) capable of generating >1 million trips for CityMoS traffic simulator.
- \cdot Implemented a taxi state machine model in CityMoS (C++) to support simulations of >100000 taxi vehicles.
- · Part of a 4-person team that enabled a Singapore-wide study of electrified public and private transportation systems.
- · Assisted in comparative analysis of traffic simulators MATSim, SimMobility, VISSIM, and CityMoS.

Research Engineer

Nanyang Technological University (NTU)

July 2017 - November 2019, Singapore

- Implemented network simulations (C++) to carry out truck platooning studies with 1000 vehicles.
- · Published an article on the impact of channel crowding and packet loss on the truck platooning performance.
- · Modeled e-bikes in the mobility simulation and developed scenarios to model their interactions with pedestrians.
- · Completed 2 individual research projects and assisted the other 3 projects within the team.

Software Engineer

Accenture

November 2013 - June 2015, Bengaluru, India

- · Saved 80% of the human time in multiple repetitive tasks through my automation solutions.
- Primary responsibility to maintain C++ and bash scripts because of my familiarity with programming.
- \cdot Top performer award within a short period led to an early promotion with best remarks.

SKILLS

Programming: Rust, C++, Python, Java

Simulators: CityMoS (C++), Disolv (Rust), and ns-3 (C++)

Others: Git, SQLite, polars, flower, OMNeT++, MATLAB, VISSIM

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Automation and Control

National University of Singapore (NUS) · Singapore, Singapore · 2016 · 3.75/5.0

 $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Published a research article on the study of a mobile robot navigation method.

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SDM College of Engineering and Technology (SDMCET) \cdot Dharwad, India \cdot 2013 \cdot 8.94/10

• Published a research article on simulation of controllers for AC Transmission.